culinate.com 2009-06-19

# Privacy Policy :: Culinate

As individuals, we value our own privacy; as a company, we value yours. The information you give to Culinate stays with us, and we protect it diligently. We do not give out your information on our website, nor do we sell or rent any personally identifying information to any of our advertisers and partners unless you have previously requested we do so.

That said, we do gather information about you to help personalize and enrich your experience on our website. Please take a few minutes to review the details below about Culinate’s privacy commitment to our users. 

### Information Collection and Use by Culinate

##### Updated January 23, 2008

**Visitors typically browse Culinate in one of two ways:**

  1. You can browse without entering any personal information and thereby remain anonymous during your visit. In this case, Culinate logs IP addresses, browser types, referring sites, and page hits, but we do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that a user’s session will be tracked, but the user will remain anonymous. We do this for systems-administration purposes, and these logs will be constantly analyzed to improve the value of the materials available on the website.
  2. You can browse as a registered user and thereby make use of the website’s personalization features. A registered user is asked to create a username and supply a valid email address, ZIP code, and possibly some optional demographic information. We use this information to identify you for personalized services on the site (recipes, comments, feedback, etc.), as well as customizing local features based on optional information. We personalize your Culinate experience by using this information to help shape our recommendations about the features, recipes, resources, and other information that might be of interest to you. We may share aggregate demographic information with our advertisers and partners so that they know the type of people they are reaching on the Culinate site, but this information is anonymous, and we do not share your email address or otherwise identify you specifically in that data.

**Member Posting of Information:** Culinate offers its users many opportunities for posting comments online. We grant this ability only to registered users, so that we can hold people responsible for their postings or verify changes as necessary. We are not responsible for what you post, but will operate in good faith and in as timely a manner as possible to correct or withdraw information as deemed appropriate in our User Agreement. 

**Use of Cookies:** Culinate uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences and to record session information. Cookies have various purposes; they help us ensure that visitors are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements, for example, and they help us customize feeds, advertising, requested correspondence, and website content based on browser type and user-profile information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or to notify you when a cookie is set. However, you must enable cookies from Culinate.com in order to use most functions on the site. See also Third-Party Advertising, below.

**Third-Party Advertising:** Ads on Culinate may be delivered to users by Culinate or by one of our advertising partners. Our partners may set cookies, allowing their ad servers to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements. We always advise reviewing the privacy policy for any third-party site you may visit.

**Links:** Culinate contains links to other websites. Please be aware that our privacy policy does not apply to these linked sites. 

**Updating Your Information:** If you would like to correct, update, or change your registration information or password, please use the My Account link.

**Security:** Culinate member accounts are secured by member-created passwords. We take precautions to ensure that member-account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer-service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time. For additional information about the security measures we use on Culinate, please contact us at [privacy@culinate.com](mailto:privacy@culinate.com).

**Sharing and Disclosure of Collected Information:** Culinate does not sell, trade, or otherwise distribute your personal information to others. We may provide aggregate statistics about our users, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information. Culinate may release account information when we believe, in good faith, that such release is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with law, (ii) enforce or apply the terms of any of our service agreements, or (iii) protect the rights, property, or safety of Culinate, our users, or others.

**Changes in Our Privacy Policy:** From time to time, Culinate may make changes to our privacy policy. If we make changes, we will post them on our site, so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. Users are bound by any minor changes to the policy when they use the site after those changes have been posted. If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify them by posting a notice on our website.

If you have comments, concerns, or feedback on our privacy policy, please email us at [privacy@culinate.com](mailto:privacy@culinate.com).
